<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tyler littlefield</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tyler littlefield</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Sets</title>
      <link>/post/comparing-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/comparing-sets/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The task of comparing sets (unique vectors) is a common one, we often want to confirm whether two things are the same or not. For example, we might rewrite a function to make it run faster, in this case we want to make sure that the new and old function output the same result. On the other hand, we might rewrite a function to fix a bug, in this context we want to make sure the output of the new function is different, potentially resolving the bug and producing the correct output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iteration the Easy Way</title>
      <link>/post/iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/iteration/</guid>
      <description>I do not come from a computer science background but my guess is that base R’s apply family of functions stand out as something strange. This strangeness might be because for loops are explicit and make it clear what’s going on, so why obfuscate the logic?
But on the other hand, I think you could argue that while the logic might be clear, the intent isn’t, at least not immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First CRAN Package</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-cran-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-cran-package/</guid>
      <description>Thanks, your package is on its way to CRAN.
 Introduction I am really excited to announce (12 days late) that lisa is on CRAN, my first R package available on the Comprehensive R Archive Network! This was a pretty big deal for me because I have wanted to submit something to CRAN for a couple of years now.
Anyway, lisa is a color palette pacakge, it provides R users with 128 color palettes based on artwork from the worlds greatest artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Shiny Code</title>
      <link>/post/modular-shiny-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modular-shiny-code/</guid>
      <description>Intro In 2016, Garrett Grolemond gave a talk at the very first Shiny Developer Conference in Palo Alto, California. The first slide in his presentation read in big bold letters, “Writing Big Apps, How to use Shiny Modules”. You can find the slides here and a video of the talk here.
In a nutshell, shiny modules allow users to write composable shiny code. Little bite size pieces of code that can be reused and brought together to work as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Equality of Multiple Expressions</title>
      <link>/post/testing-equality-of-multiple-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/testing-equality-of-multiple-expressions/</guid>
      <description>Credit to BrodieG: https://stackoverflow.com/questions/27325005
This post is essentially an extension of a previous post I wrote. The only addition is a cool idea for testing near equality of outputs. I’m calling this an “equality matrix”, a matrix of methods that displays whether or not they are equal to each other. One use case is benchmarking. As we benchmark multiple solutions to a single problem, testing whether or not the outputs are equal becomes more time consuming as the all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility</title>
      <link>/post/reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reproducibility/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to SO. In order to answer your question, please provide a minimal, complete, and verifiable example.
 If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever asked a question on Stack Overflow (SO), you may recognize the quote above. This is because reproducibility is incredibly important when asking programming questions and it&amp;rsquo;s often overlooked. To be brief, a great reproducible example should be:
 Minimal &amp;ndash; Provide the least amount of code needed to reproduce the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>